What is hidden in snow, comes forth in the thaw.
The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo is a thriller, crime,
mystery film directed by David Fincher.
Disgraced journalist Mikael Blomkvist investigates the
disappearance of a weary patriarch's niece from 40 years ago.
He is aided by the pierced, tattooed, punk
computer hacker named Lisbeth Salander.
As they work together in the investigation, Blomkvist and Salander uncover
immense corruption beyond anything they have ever imagined.
Mikael Blomkvist, played by Daniel Craig.
Lisbeth Salander, played by Rooney Mara.
Henrik Vanger, played by Christopher Plummer.
Martin Vanger, played by Stellan Skarsgård.
Erika Berger, played by Robin Wright.
Nils Bjurman, played by Yorick van Wageningen.
The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo is a 2011 neo-noir mystery thriller film
directed by David Fincher from a screenplay by Steven Zaillian.
It is based on the 2005 novel of the same name by Stieg Larsson.
Starring Daniel Craig as journalist Mikael Blomkvist and Rooney Mara as Lisbeth Salander, it tells the story of Blomkvist's
investigation to find out what happened to a girl from a wealthy family who had disappeared 40 years earlier.
He recruits the help of Salander, a computer hacker.
Sony Pictures began development on the film in 2009.
It took the company a few months to obtain the film adaptation rights to
the novel, while also recruiting Zaillian and Fincher.
The casting process for the lead roles was intense; Craig faced scheduling conflicts,
and a number of actresses were sought for the role of Lisbeth Salander.
The script took over six months to write, which
included three months of analyzing the novel.
The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo premiered at Odeon Leicester Square in London on December 12, 2011,
and was released in the United States on December 21, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film grossed $232.6 million against a $90 million production budget and received acclaim from critics, with praise for
Craig and Mara's performances as well as Fincher's direction, the score, and the film's tone and visuals.
The film was chosen by the National Board of Review as one of the top ten films of 2011 and was a candidate for numerous awards, winning, among others, the Academy
Award for Best Film Editing, while Mara's performance earned her a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actress at the 84th Academy Awards.
A soft reboot and sequel, The Girl in the Spider's
Web, was released in October 2018.
The film explores themes of journalist, island,
rape, hacker, based on novel or book.
The tone is mind_bending and intense.